# Kristijan Perusko

## software engineer

#### Contact

kristijan.perusko@yahoo.com

#### Links

Linkedin:// kperusko Github:// kperusko Bitbucket:// kperusko

#### Languages

English, Croatian

### **Programming**

Experience using: PHP, JavaScript HTML & CSS

Familiar with: Java, Python C# (Silverlight), VB.Net Scala, Racket, Octave

#### Db

MongoDB, MySQL

#### Os

Ubuntu, Debian Fedora, CentOS Windows

#### **Additional**

Git, Mercurial, SVN Apache2, RabbitMQ AWS, S3, Heroku

# **Summary**

I've worked as a full stack and back-end software engineer. I prefer working with algorithms, databases, implementing APIs and doing system-wide optimizations, because I find them more challenging and therefore more interesting. This said, I would love to work more with functional programming.

# **Experience**

2008-2014 **Novatec** 

In-house software engineer for my first two years. Became team leader building client's booking system and multiple customer-facing sites. Also served as project leader where I gathered requirements from clients, mentored junior engineers, planned and implemented critical features. My responsibilities included administration and optimization of MongoDB and MySQL DBs and Ubuntu/Debian servers.

Team leader | Software engineer

2007-2008 **Tempo** IT administrator

Responsible for Windows administration and user support, configuration and management of infrastructure and equipment in 8 remote offices. Managed system upgrade for compliance with EU customs legislation.

grade for compliance with Lo customs leg

2005-2007 **Vlado elektronika** Sofware and electrical QA engineer

Created hardware testbed and software for computer aided testing of intrusion alarm system. This system automated 90% of the tests and lowered the testing time by 60%.

# **Education**

2013	BS of information tehnology	Veleuciliste u Rijeci (Rijeka College)

Silverlight 5 and MS Sync Framework

DC servo driver controlled by IR remote

2002 **Electrical engineering** Mate Blazina High School

# Courses online

07 2014	<b>M202: MongoDB Advanced Deployment and Operations</b> <i>MongoDB</i>	MongoDB
11 2013	<b>Principles of Reactive Programming</b> École Polytechnique Fédérale de Lausanne	Coursera
10 2013	Machine Learning Stanford University	Coursera
10 2013	Interactive Programming in Python Rice University	Coursera
10 2013	M101JS MongoDB for Node.js Developers  MongoDB	MongoDB
09 2013	<b>Functional Programming Principles in Scala</b> <i>Ecole Polytechnique Federale de Lausanne</i>	Coursera
06 2013	Startup Engineering Stanford University	Coursera